そうか…
ゼロの正体は お前だったのか
I see...
You were Zero all along.
Someone with a grudge against
the Britannian imperial family...
ブリタニア皇族に対する恨み
ダールトンの分析は当たっていたな
Darlton's analysis was correct.
Y- You did this all
for Nunnally's sake?
ナ… ナナリーの為に こんな事を？
Correct.
そうです　私は今の世界を破壊し
新しい時代を創る
I will destroy the present world
and build a new one in its place.
You killed them for the
sake of that madness?!
そんな世迷言の為に殺したのか？
クロヴィスを… ユフィまで！
Clovis? Even Euphy?!
You're one to talk, sister, considering how
you idolized my mother, Marianne the Flash.
姉上こそ 私の母
閃光のマリアンヌに憧れていたくせに
ふっ どうやら これ以上の会話に
意味はないようだな
It would seem...
Any further talk with you would be useless.
そうですね　ならば
Indeed. Well, then...
Lelouch vi Britannia
orders you to answer him!
ルルーシュ・ヴィ・ブリタニアが
問いに答えよ
Right.
ああ
私の母を殺したのは姉上ですか？
Sister, were you the one
who killed my mother?
No.
違う
Then who was it?
では誰が？
I don't know.
分からない
ああっ？
あの時の警護担当は姉上でしたね？
You were in charge of her
personal guard, were you not?!
ああ
Yes.
Then why did you
withdraw her escort?
なぜ警護隊を引き上げたのですか？
頼まれたから
Because I was asked to.
誰に？
By whom?!
Lady Marianne.
マリアンヌ様
ああっ！
母さんに？　まさか そんな…
Mother did?! That's impossible!
Are you saying Mother knew
she would be attacked that day?!
という事は 母さんは あの日
襲撃がある事を知っていた？
No, it's impossible! If she did,
she would have gotten us out of there!
いや あり得ない
なら俺達を逃がしているはず
What happened on that day?!
Who killed my mother?!
何があった？　あの日
誰なんだ！　母さんを殺した奴は？
あっ ああ…
くっ！　知らないのか…
You don't know?
Then who knows the truth?!
なら 真実を知っている奴は誰だ？
調べていたんだろ？　あの日の事を
I know you've investigated
what happened that day yourself!
His Majesty the Emperor ordered Schneizel
to transport the body out of there.
皇帝陛下に命じられて
シュナイゼル兄様が遺体を運び出した
遺体って母さんの？
じゃあ あの棺の中…
The body? You mean mother's?
Then what was in that coffin?
おい 戻って来い！
Hey! Get back in here!
I know! The government bureau
defense forces will be here soon.
分かっている
そろそろ政庁の守備隊が…
No! Your little sister's
been kidnapped!
違う！　お前の妹がさらわれた！
ん？　冗談を聞いている暇はない
今はコーネリアを人質として本陣に…
This is no time for jokes.
Now we have to take Cornelia
to headquarters as our hostage.
I just know this!
It's the reason you have for living!
私には分かる！
お前が生きる目的なのだろう？
神根島に向かっている！
She's headed for Kamine Island!
ん？　神根島？
Kamine Island?
ALL HAIL BRITANNIA!
オール・ハイル・ブリターニアー！
What's this?
Can it really be? Zero?!
おや あなた様は？　ゼロ！
Oh, what luck!
What fate! What evil fortune!
なんたる ぎょう倖！　宿命！　数奇！
まさか オレンジか？
Is that you, Orange?
お お お… お願いです
死んで頂けますか？
Oh! Oh!
Oh, I beg of you!
Will you please die?
Dammit... Get Cornelia!
コーネリア！
分かっている
I know!
あー ああ…
ああ！
Zero! I...
ゼロ 私は…
帝国臣民の敵を排除せよ
I shall eliminate all enemies
of our empire's subjects!
そう ならばこそ
オール・ハイル・ブリターニア！
Yes! And so...
ALL HAIL BRITANNIA!
あっ このような失態
我が君に なんと報告すれば…
Such a disgrace!
How do I report this to the prince?
情念だけが暴走しています
さすがに行動予測までは…
It's just his emotions which are running wild.
It's hard to predict his actions.
I just wish we could
communicate with him!
せめて会話が可能な
状態であれば良かったんだが
ええーい 邪魔をするな！
Out of my way!
ゼーロー！
ZERO-O-O!!!
痛む場所は 誰にも云わない
itamu basho darenimo iwanai
I don't tell anyone where I hurt
急ぐ心が 隠した夢を
isogu kokoro ga kakushita yume wo
I stare at the dreams hidden by my hurried heart
壊れそうな 瞳で見つめる
kowaresouna hitomi de mitsumeru
With fragile eyes
押さえきれない チカラだけ
osaekirenai chikara dake
Only my unchecked power
離さずに 翔び立つ
hanasazu ni tobitatsu
Flies out without separating from me
meguriai ga ugokidasu
Chance encounters hasten...
巡り逢いが 動き出す
運命を早めて
unmei wo hayamete
Destiny as it starts to move
せめて君が駆け抜ける
semete kimi ga kakenukeru
At least tell me the instant...
一瞬を 教えて
isshun wo oshiete
When you come running through
現在 ホズイトエリアを通過
ZERO
どうして スザク君を止めたんですか？
Why did you stop Suzaku?
軍属としては当たり前でしょ？
It was my duty as a civilian
military contractor, wasn't it?
You didn't want him
to get killed, did you?
死なせたく なかったんですね？
Please, you know me
better than that.
まさか 君も知ってるくせに
あ…
人間はとても壊れやすいって
その肉体も 心も 互いの関係も
Humans are so fragile... In our bodies,
our hearts, and our relationships with each other.
だからといって
思い通りになる人や世界なんて
Nevertheless, you can't bend people
or the world to the way you want.
でも 僕はそういうパーツが欲しいんだ
But I want that sort of part.
枢木少佐がダメなら
次のデヴァイサーを探すだけさ
If Major Kururugi turns out to be no good,
we'll just look for the next Devicer.
気をつけなさいよー！
Be careful! A Knightmare that
enters the field will shut down.
ナイトメアは フィールドの中だと
止まっちゃうんだから
分かっています
Understood.
あっ ううっ…
ふん！
器用だな
Not bad.
扇か？　私だ
Ohgi? It's me.
ゼロ よかった
Zero! Thank God!
ん？　南？　扇はどうした？
Hm? Minami? Where's Ohgi?
撃たれたんだ
手当てしてるが意識がない
He's been shot! We're treating him,
but he's unconscious.
それと 犯人はまだ…
And the culprit's still...
分かった ならお前でいい
車椅子の少女はどうした？
All right, you'll do.
Where's the girl in the wheelchair?
あっ いや それより扇が…
Um, doesn't Ohgi come first?
代わりなら あとで手配する
今は車椅子の少女が先だ！
I'll arrange a replacement later!
The girl in the wheelchair comes first!
代わりって…
Replacement?!
確認しろ！　早く！
Confirm her location!
Hurry!
拘束していた学生達はみんな消えたよ
扇が撃たれた どさくさに…
All the students we had
confined disappeared.
In the confusion
when Ohgi was shot...
あっ…
あっ ルルーシュか？
悪いけど今は…
Lelouch! Sorry, but I'm kinda busy.
ナナリーはそこにいるか？
Is Nunnally there with you?!
クラブハウスにいるよ
俺達はちょっと離れちゃってるけど
She's in the clubhouse.
We're a short distance away.
分かった！
Understood!
あっ おい そっちは今どこに…
Hey! Where are you?!
あっ！
ええーい！　ナナリーには繋がらないし
咲世子も
I can't get through to
Nunnally or even Sayoko!
ルルーシュ 私は お前の共犯者だ
お前の味方だ
Lelouch, I'm your accomplice.
Your ally.
信じろと？
理由すら言わない女の戯言を
So, I should just trust you? The word of
a woman who won't give me the reason?
お前に死なれては困る　それは本当だ
I don't want you to die.
That part is true!
ふん！　一方的な都合ばかり
Hmpf! That's just
one-sided convenience!
三番隊 敵の飛行型だ
一斉射で撃ち落せ
Squad 3, enemy aircraft!
Synch fire and shoot it down!
了解！　敵機捕捉
Roger! Tracking enemy... Fire!
撃てー！
んん…
見えた 見えた…
I see them... I see them...
なっ なんだあれは？
Wh- What the hell is it?!
C- Captain Kagezaki!
影崎隊長！
ゼロ ゼロよー！
Zero! ZERO!!!
雑魚が！
お前の相手をしている暇はない
Cannon fodder!
I don't have time to fool with you!
C.C. 12ストリートに出ろ！
C.C.! Pop out on 12th street!
一方的な都合ばかり！
Speaking of one-sided
convenience!
当たらず
このジェレミア・ゴットバルトには！
You can't hit me!
Not Jeremiah Gottwald!
違うな オレンジ君　もう当たっている
Wrong, my dear Orange.
You're being hit right now.
卑怯　後ろをバック
Coward!
You strike from behind?
潰れろ 古き者よ
Be smashed, you relic!
よし これでナナリーの元に
All right,
now to get to Nunnally.
えい
えっ
かあー！　頑丈だなあ
やっぱ回転刃刀がいるかあ
Oh... That's a solid hatch!
If only we had a
rotating cutting blade.
玉城さん　こいつら どうしますか？
他の学生達と一緒に 寮か体育館に
Tamaki, what do we do
with these ones?
Lock them in the dorms or
the gym with the other students?
学生？
Students?
ゼロ呼んで！
Call Zero!
あっ
くっ！
ゼロは絶対に私達を守るから
でなきゃ変だもの 今までの事だって！
I guarantee Zero will protect us!
If he doesn't, something's wrong!
He's done it all along...
うるせえ！　ゼロの事は
この俺が一番よく知ってんだよ！
Shut up!
I know Zero better than anyone!
こんな時あいつなら
迷わないって事もなあ
He wouldn't hesitate
at a time like this!
やめろ！
Stop!
あっ
あっ なんだよ
ブリキの為なら外に出るってか？
Oh, what's this?
You'll come out to help Brits, huh?
Suzaku...
スザク…
欲しいのは その白兜だけだ
裏切り者は ここで死んでおけ
All we want is the white helmet.
A traitor like you
can die right here!
うぎゃー！
うわあ がっ！
Wha?!
フーッ！
アーサー
Arthur!
このクソ猫が！
もういい こいつら全員始末…
Goddamn cat!
Screw this! Kill 'em all!
あっ
こんばんは
Evening, folks!
えっ？
引けー！　ひとまず引くんだー！
Retreat! Retreat for now!
ああ まさか あのプリン伯爵が
前線に出て来るなんて！
Impossible! The Earl of Pudding
came out to the front lines?!
ラクシャータ やっぱりいたのか
Rakshata... I thought it was you.
今よ！
Now!
あっ
Gotcha!
待て てめーら！
Stop, you!
おっ く…
ええーい
どう？　セシル君
テストパーツの調子は？
Well, Miss Cécile?
How are the test parts working out?
いけそうですね 実用化
Looks like we can put them to use.
戻った
It's back!
フィラーカバーを開けて
エナジーを交換するわ
Open your filler cover.
I'll exchange energy with you.
はい　でも どうしてセシルさんまで
Right! But Miss Cécile,
why did you come out here, too?
どうしてですか？　ロイドさん
Why did we, Lloyd?
取り返しに来ただけだよ
ランスロットとか まあ色々と
We just came to take back the Lancelot!
And do a few other things.
サザーランドのパーツだけど
いけそう？
They're Sutherland parts,
but they should work.
はい 適合チェック クリアです
Right. It's cleared the
compatibility check.
じゃあ ここは私達に任せて
あなたはゼロを
All right, leave this place to us.
You go after Zero!
あっ… ありがとうございます
Thank you. Protect Ashford
Academy and everyone here!
アッシュフォード学園を
ここのみんなをお願いします
分かってるよ 婚約者もいるしね
Understood.
My fiancée is here too, after all.
あっ ロイヤルプライベート？
"Royal private?"
く… 枢木君
K- Kururugi...?
コーネリア総督？
Viceroy Cornelia?!
しぶとい さすがはコーネリアの精鋭
Damn their tenacity!
Just what you'd expect of Cornelia's elite!
藤堂 以降の作戦は全てお前に任せる
Tohdoh! I'm leaving all operations
from here on in your hands!
ん？
負傷した扇の仕事は
ディートハルトに仕切らせろ
Ohgi's been wounded,
so have Diethard assume his duties!
任せる？　任せるとは いったい？
"Leaving" them to me?
What do you mean?!
私は 他にやらなければ
ならない事がある
There's something else
that I have to do!
以降 そちらからの通信は全て切る
I will not respond to any
more communications from you!
ま 待て！　この状況で他があるのか！
W- Wait! What else could possibly
be more important in this situation?!
七番隊 全滅！
Squad 7, wiped out!
何？
What?!
ええーい！
落ち着いてー！
大丈夫だから順番にね 下級生から
Keep calm! You're safe,
so wait your turn! Youngest students first!
ひとまず下がるんだ！
We gotta fall back for now!
持ち出せないデータは処分しろ！
Destroy any data you can't take!
早く！　早く！
Hurry! Hurry!
あっ あ…
せ… 戦況は 我が軍に有利だ
This... this battle situation
has turned to my side's favor...
いいか… 私の負傷は
極力伏せろ… 動揺する
Am I clear? Do all you can to hide
the fact that I've been wounded.
It'll just upset them...
Guilford...
ギルフォードや…
グラストンナイツが…
And the Glaston Knights...
しかし お前にだけは…
However...
You're the only one I can tell...
もう しゃべらないで下さい
Don't talk anymore.
Kamine Island...
That's where Zero's headed.
神根島… そこに ゼロが…
ああっ
それ以外は… ダメだ 思い出せない
Any more than that...
It's no use. I can't remember.
ギアス
Geass!
お前はユフィの騎士なのだろう？
ならば行ってユフィの汚名をすすぐのだ
You're Euphy's knight, aren't you?
Then go and clear
her dishonored name!
あっ はい
Y- Yes!
貴公に 略式ではあるが
ブリタニアの騎士候位を授ける
This may be a little informal,
but I dub thee Knight of Honor of Britannia.
これで名実共にお前は騎士だ
You are now knight
in both name and title.
行け 枢木スザクよ
Now go, Suzaku Kururugi!
イエス ユア・ハイネス
Yes, Your Highness!
え？　ゼロがいなくなったのですか？
What? Zero's disappeared?
いいえ 指揮権を現場に 委ねただけで
No, he's just transferred
command to us on-site here.
はい
Right.
なぜ こんな大事な時に…
Why?! Why now, of all times?!
なんで扇が撃たれたんだ？
ゼロは どこにいるんだよお？
Why was Ohgi shot?!
Where the hell is Zero?!
知らないって！
I said I don't know!
連絡は取れないのか？
Can't you contact him?!
逃げる理由なんて ないはずよねえ？
でも…
He had no reason
to run away, and yet...
いくら藤堂さんでも
全体状況が分からないと
As good as Tohdoh is,
if we don't know the overall situation...
ゼロ 私はどうすれば…？
Zero, what should I do?
カ… カレン
K- Kallen...
扇さん 大丈夫なんですか？
Ohgi! Are you all right?!
ああ それより カレン ゼロを追え
Yeah... Anyway, Kallen...
Go after Zero!
あっ
彼の 行動には… 意味が… あるはず
There must be... a reason...
he's acting this way...
助けるんだ ゼロ…
ナオトの 夢を… 継ぐ者…
Save him... Zero...
The one who will realize...
Naoto's dream...
でも どうやって探せば？
But how do I find him?!
そろそろ見えるだろう
You should see him soon...
ええ？
あれは… ランスロット
あいつがここを離れる理由なんて
That's... Lancelot! What would be
drawing him away from here?
ラクシャータが 発信機を な…
Rakshata...
Heard a transmission...
分かりました
Understood!
補給部隊！　接収した空輸機を
私に回せ！　最優先だ！
Supply corps!
Send a captured air transport to me!
Top priority!
チクショー！
せめて ここだけでも！
Dammit! Can't we at least
hold this place?!
学生さん達の搭乗完了までだよ？
頑張ってね
It's just till the students
are all aboard. Hang in there.
分かっています
Understood.
ええっ？
どうしてあんな所に熱源反応が？
Why am I reading a thermal
reaction in there?!
ナイトメア？
A Knightmare!
なんだい？　あの年代もんは
What's that relic doing here?
ガニメデ？
The Ganymede...
ニーナ！
Nina!
いけない！　砲撃中止
黒の騎士団もストップ！
Oh, hell! Cease fire!
Black Knights, you, too!
はあ？
Huh?
一時休戦だ！
そいつを撃っちゃいけない！
A temporary truce!
We can't fire on that thing!
みんな！　言う通りにおし！
撃つんじゃないよ
Everyone, do what he says!
Cease fire!
ロイドをマジにするほどの代物か？
If it's got Lloyd that
panicked, then!
はあー
ニーナ 完成させたのかい？
Nina, did you complete it?
検証は不十分です
爆発させられるかは分かりません
There wasn't time to test it.
I don't know if it'll explode.
でも 私は…
But still, I...
爆発って何言ってるの ニーナ！
あっ！
Nina, what do you mean, "explode?!"
危険よ！　下がって！
It's dangerous! Stay back!
彼女の理論通りなら
If her theory is correct,
このトウキョウ租界そのものが
死滅するかも
that thing may destroy
the entire Tokyo settlement.
ええっ？
んな事あるはず…
That's imposs...
信じなさいよ！
Believe it!
She's even used Sakuradite in it!
ん？
サクラダイトまで使ってんだから
あっ
Zero... Where is Zero? Tell me.
Princess Euphemia will be avenged!
ゼロはどこ？
教えて… ユーフェミア様の仇
ゼロは どこにいるのよー！
WHERE IS ZERO?!!!
ナナリーがいなくなったら
俺は今まで なんの為に
If Nunnally is lost,
what have I been fighting for till now?!
なんの為の独立戦争だ
ユフィまで犠牲にして
What's the point of this
war of independence?
Why did Euphy
have to be sacrificed?!
見えたぞ 神根島だ
I can see Kamine Island now.
あっ
取り返す 誰が相手だろうと
ナナリーを！
I'm taking Nunnally back,
no matter who tries to stop me!
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
やはり ここだろうな
何かお前に関係がある場所か？
I figured it was here.
Is this place somehow related to you?
ここは知らない
I don't know this place.
ふっ 他にもあるという事か
Meaning there are others like it?
ナナリーをさらった奴は
ギアス能力者か？
Does the one who took
Nunnally have a Geass power?
I don't know that much.
そこまでは分からない
んん…
It's the truth.
本当だ
I'll believe you.
At the very least, we're still accomplices.
信じよう
少なくとも 我々の共犯関係は
まだ続いているのだから
Thank you.
ありがとう
うっ
どうした？
What is it?!
I see! This is!
そうか これは！
あっ！
What?!
何？　ああっ
落ち着け
これは侵入者に対してのトラップ
Calm down! This is a trap set for intruders.
The one who activated it is...
作動させた奴が…
ああっ
ううっ
What is this? The past?
なんだ これは？
昔の？　C.C.！
C.C.! No... But!
いや… しかし…
なんだ お前は！
Who are you?!
あっ ああー！
やめろ… やめろー！
Stop it...
STOP IT!!!
C.C.... Are these your?
C.C.これは  お前の…
All I have left are my
memories as a witch.
残っているのは魔女としての記憶だけ
I don't know if I was
ever human to begin with.
そもそも自分が人間だったのかすら
分かりはしない
私を憎む人も 優しくしてくれた人も
全て時の流れの中に消えていった
All the people who have hated me or
who have treated me with kindness...
They've all vanished
into the flow of time.
果てる事のない時の流れの中で
私 ひとり…
Within the endless flow of eternity,
I am all alone.
ひとりじゃないだろう？
You're not alone!
え？
俺達は共犯者 お前が魔女ならば
俺が魔王になれば いいだけだ
We're accomplices.
If you're a witch,
then I can be a warlock.
ふっ こんな時によく言う
That's a hell of a thing to say
at a time like this.
C.C., are you all right?
C.C.無事か？
Who do you think you're talking to?
誰に向かって言っている？
うっ
私です　ゼロよ 懺悔は今！
Zero! It is I!
Now, repent!
しつこい奴！
You stubborn fool!
ううっ コーネリアに受けた
破損箇所が！
The point that Cornelia
damaged before!
ううっ ハドロン砲も あと１撃しか…
The Hadron Cannon only
has one shot left!
私の素晴らしき雪辱！
My magnificent vengeance!
ううっ 姑息 孤立 小癪！
Makeshift, one-shot, and impudent!
あいつは私に任せろ！
お前はナナリーを！
Leave him to me!
You go after Nunnally!
But, we're out of energy!
しかし もうエナジーが…
大丈夫だ
I'll be okay!
はあ  いや… 少し不安だな
Actually, I'm a little nervous.
ん？
勝てよ ルルーシュ　自らの過去に
そして 行動の結果に
Win, Lelouch.
Over your own past.
And over the outcome of your actions.
C.C. 死ぬなよ
C.C., don't die!
誰に言っている
Who are you talking to?
ふっ そうだったな
You have a point.
発見！
I've found you!
You're not who I'd choose
to commit suicide with, but...
心中相手としては好みじゃないが
おおー！
守り抜け！　我らの勝利は目前だ！
Hold the line!
Victory is within sight!
Dammit, we can't hold out!
ああっ 押し切れない！
If we don't hurry,
the enemy reinforcements will arrive!
早くしないと 敵の援軍が…
どうすりゃいいんだ？
What should we do?!
うっ
Inoue...
井上… 何やってんだ？　ゼロはー！
Where the hell is Zero?!
全軍 突撃！
反乱軍を 一挙に粉砕する！
All forces, charge!
We'll crush the rebels with one blow!
Fight to your last breath!
No matter what!
死守しろ　なんとしても
ここを破られたら
完全に我が軍は崩壊する！
If they break through here,
our forces will collapse completely!
藤堂の軍事的手腕が
劣っている訳ではない
It's not that Tohdoh isn't
as good a military leader.
But he lacks the charisma
which Zero possesses!
カリスマ… ゼロには それがある
なのに ここまできて まさか…
Even so, to have come this far,
and now we're!
ゼロ様 本当に私達を
日本を見捨てたのですか？
Master Zero,
have you really abandoned us?
Have you abandoned Japan?
入り口にあったトラップは
時間稼ぎだろう
Their trap at the entrance
was to buy time.
目的は俺か？　C.C.という線もあるが…
Was I the target?
Or was it C.C.?
No matter. First thing to do
is make sure Nunnally is all right.
いずれにせよ
ナナリーの無事を確認してからだな
あっ
こちらを向け ゆっくりと
Turn and face me. Slowly.
Dammit! Now, of all times!
ええーい！　こんな時に…
聞こえなかったのか？　ゼロ
Didn't you hear me, Zero?
こちらを向くんだ ゆっくりと
Turn and face me. Slowly.
Euphemia arbitrarily murdered innocent
Japanese people. You'd fight for a woman like...
ユーフェミアは
罪なき日本人を一方的に殺した
君は そんな女を…
That Geass power of yours
is very convenient, isn't it?
便利な力だな ギアスとは
あっ
自らは影に隠れ
責任は全て他者に なすりつける
You get to hide in the shadows
while others take all the blame.
傲慢にして卑劣　それがお前の本質だ
An arrogant coward.
That's your true nature.
カレン！
Kallen!
ああっ！
君も ゼロの正体を知りたくはないか？
Don't you want to know
Zero's true identity, too?
What are you saying now?!
何を今さら
君にも立ち会う権利がある
You also have a right
to bear witness.
あっ 待てー！
Wait!
How? Why?!
なんで？　どうして？
うっ…
信じたくは なかったよ
I didn't want to believe it.
ル… ルルーシュが？
L- Lelouch is?
Yes, I'm Zero.
そうだ　俺がゼロだ
黒の騎士団を率い
神聖ブリタニア帝国に挑み
The man who leads the Black Knights,
who challenges the Holy Britannian Empire,
そして 世界を手に入れる男だ
and who holds the
entire world in his hand.
あっ…
あなたは 私達 日本人を
利用していたの？　私の事も…
You used us Japanese...
You used me?!
結果的に日本は解放される
文句はないだろう
Japan will be freed as a result.
You've nothing to complain about, surely.
ああ…
I should have
arrested you sooner.
早く 君を逮捕すべきだったよ
You realized it was me?
気づいていたのか？
確信はなかった
だから否定し続けてきた
I wasn't sure,
so I kept denying it to myself.
君を信じたかったから
I wanted to believe in you.
But you were lying to us.
To me, to Euphy... Even to Nunnally!
だけど君は嘘をついたね
僕とユフィに ナナリーに
Yes, and now Nunnally's
been kidnapped!
ああ そのナナリーがさらわれた
えっ？
スザク 一時休戦といかないか？
ナナリーを救う為に力を貸して欲しい
Suzaku, can't we have a temporary truce?!
I want your help to save Nunnally!
俺とお前 ２人いれば
できない事なんて…
There's nothing you
and I can't accomplish!
Don't be a fool!
甘えるな！
うっ
その前に手を組むべきは ユフィだった
君とユフィが力を合わせれば 世界を…
You should have joined up
with Euphy first!
If you and Euphy and joined forces,
the world could have been!
That's all in the past! It's done!
全ては過去 終わった事だ
過去？
The past?!
You killed your own father, didn't you?!
お前も父親を殺しているだろう
懺悔など あとでいくらでもできる
You can find time for regrets later!
いいや 君には無理だ！
No, you're hopeless!
What?
何？
君は… 最後の最後に世界を裏切り
世界に裏切られた！
In the very end, you'd betray the
entire world, like it's betrayed you!
I can't let your dream
be realized!
君の願いは 叶えてはいけない！
バカめ 理想だけで世界が動くものか！
You fool! You think ideals alone
can change the world?!
さあ 撃てるものなら撃ってみろ！
流体サクラダイトをな
Then go on!
Shoot me if you're going to!
And shoot this
liquid Sakuradite, too!
ああっ！
俺の心臓が止まったら爆発する
お前達もおしまいだ
If my heart stops, it'll explode!
You both will die with me!
Damn you!
貴様！
I'll make a deal with you.
それより取り引きだ
お前にギアスを教えたのは誰だ？
Who told you about Geass?
Did they take Nunnally?!
そいつとナナリーは？
ここから先の事は お前には関係ない！
Nothing that happens now
is any of your business!
Your very existence is a mistake!
お前の存在が間違っていたんだ！
ああ…
お前は世界から はじき出されたんだ
ナナリーは俺が！
You have to be removed from the world!
I'll take care of Nunnally!
SUZAKU!
スザク！
LELOUCH!
ルルーシュー！
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
意味も無く繰り返し
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
過去の嘘も過ちも
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
振り返れば そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
People... humans are the
beings who look for happiness.
What the Britannian boy, Lelouch, wanted to have was
nothing but a small happiness. It's nothing special.
At least at the root of his motives,
there were only humble wishes
that were simply natural to any human.
Who could ever disclaim such dreams and such vows?
Who could ever have the right to do that?
However, whoever you might be, without choice,
you have to deal with others and with the world,
and have yourself be regulated and set down.
Therefore, in the face of the world's
wills, your personal speculations
are so ephemeral they can't help being overwhelmed.
Sins and punishments, destiny and judgment.
What stands in front of Lelouch is
the past he brought forth by himself.
Is it a hatred resulting from the
fact that humans are humans?
Nonetheless, for now, we should be grateful...
Yes, at least, to the fact that humans
are the beings who look for happiness.
A remaining piece of hopes, a faint sign
of wishes will be born from despairs.
Zero... He was a fool.
No matter how you strike back or resist,
the world never changes.
I'll tell you. In the adult world,
what's "right" has no value.
Do the powerless have no choice but to bear it?
Even when they're right?
STOP!
I'LL
LIVE
MY
LIFE!
If it's wrong to be powerless,
does having power make you right?
It wasn't me who was wrong!
It's the world!
Sequel production is moving at high gear!
Watch for it!